好吧那就更黑暗了这就更重要了
All right so that was darker compose,
this is very much more and
对你和你白天来说都很有用
one misses primary useful to you and
your day to day basis, and it's much more
以发展这种经验为中心的经验。
oriented towards development the kind of
experience as an NCICD kind of experience.
Kubernetes 非常注重生产工作负载。
Kubernetes is very much oriented
towards production workloads.
Kubernetes 是为了生产工作负载而编写的，
Kubernetes was written for
production workloads,
你大概不会想在你的电脑上运行 Kubernetes
you probably don't typically want to
run Kubernetes on your computer for
我们会讨论的一系列的原因
just a slew of reasons
that we'll talk about.
所以库伯内特
So Kubernetes.
这一部分我要告诉你
This section I'm just gonna tell you
the kind of the high level concepts of
库伯内特斯
Kubernetes, and
然后我就会给你展示一种便宜的方法向库伯内特介绍
then I'm gonna show you kind of a cheap
way to get introduced to Kubernetes.
首先你可能会看到库伯内特通常缩写为 k8s
So first of all, you'll likely see
Kubernetes often abbreviated as k8s,
在 K 和 s 之间有 8 个角色那就是从那里来的
k-8-s, cuz there's 8 characters between
k and s, that's where that comes from.
人们都懒惰，不记得怎么拼。
People are lazy and
can't remember how to spell it.
尤其是非英语的人，很难记住怎么拼
Especially for non-English speakers, it
can be difficult to remember How to spell
库伯内特，所以这就是为什么它经常如此的缩写。
Kubernetes, so
that's why its often abbreviated that way.
所以库伯内特斯
So, Kubernetes.
我喜欢告诉别人我觉得容器简单容易
I like to tell people that I think
containers are simple and more easy and
每个人都应该知道怎么用码头的容器之类的
everyone should know how to use containers
in docker, and things like that.
库伯内特很难，而且很困难。
Kubernetes is hard, and it's difficult.
不是每个人都应该懂得如何使用库伯内特。
And not everyone should
know how to use Kubernetes.
但我要教你怎么做才能让你明白
But I'm gonna show you how to do it
just so you understand what it is and so
你知道什么时候才能到达它什么时候你肯定不想去
you can know when to reach for it and when
you definitely do not wanna reach for it.
就我个人而言，我把这个比作 Redux 和反应，对，雷达克斯，
Like for me personally, I compare this
to Redux and react, right, Redux,
真的很困难而且并非总是必要的，人们仍然想知道。
it's really difficult and not always
necessary and people still wanna know it.
我要教你如何使用 Redux 我要告诉你
So I'm going to teach you how to
use Redux,and I'm gonna tell you
最重要的是不要用它，
not to use it, [LAUGH] for
the most part, and
这也是我在这里和库伯内特的观点
that's kind of what my point
here with Kubernetes as well.
这就很难了很难
Is that, it's difficult, It's hard.
它是一个复杂的产品，解决了一个复杂的问题。
It's a complicated product that
solves a complicated problem.
最重要的是你通常不需要它除非你是个大的
And for the most part, you don't
normally need it unless you are a big
公司是一家大型的，面向微型服务的大型建筑。
company that's shipping big,
micro service oriented architecture.
这个是在 Google 为 Google 问题创建的，我们大多数都不需要
This was created at Google for Google
problems and most of us don't necessarily
每天都有谷歌问题吗
have Google problems on
the day to day Okay?
所以，让我们谈谈你什么时候想用它。
So, let's talk about when
you would wanna use it.
如果你有很多容器库伯内特很有用
Kubernetes is useful if you
have a lot of containers,
有很多不同的服务对吧
a lot of different kind of services,
right?
就像我们有网络服务一样 DB 服务
Like we have the web services,
the DB service.
你有各种不同的服务
And you have all these various
different services and
他们之间的关系很复杂
they have complex relationships
between each other.
这就是 Kubernetes 非常非常有用的原因，因为你可以定义这些
That's when Kubernetes is very,
very useful because you can define these
关系，您可以定义安全规则，它可扩展得非常好。
relationships, you can define the security
rules, it scales out very well.
这是库伯内特在做的另一件事。
That's another thing that
Kubernetes is very good at doing.
装一个集装箱，做 100 个集装箱，
It's very good at taking one container and
making that 100 containers and
然后再去一个集装箱，对吧 ?
then going back down to one container,
right?
它非常非常擅长检查容器的运行状况。
It's very, very good at checking
the health of your containers.
所以如果你有 40 个容器，其中一个会开始转
So if you have like, 40 containers,
and one of them starts going wonky or
就像这样
something like that.
它可以通过健康检查来检测这个容器
It can detect that via health checks and
say cool, that container,
把它关掉，旋转一个，把它放在它的位置。
shut that one down, spin one up,
put it back in its place.
所以它真的很棒。
So it's really good at stuff like that.
这些都是非常，非常注重生产，有问题的，对吧 ?
These are all very, very production
oriented and Kind of problems, right?
让我们看看库贝尔奈特的一些基本概念和术语
Let's go over some of the fundamental
concepts and terminology of Kubernetes
你得明白这一点才能用库伯内特
cuz you kind of have to understand
this to be able to use Kubernetes.
所以当你旋转一个 " 库伯内特 " 簇的时候，第一件事就是
So when you spin up a Kubernetes cluster
of any variety, the first thing is it's
有个主人就像一个中央控制舱
gonna have a master and
that's kind of like a central control pod.
这控制了服务中的其他内容。
That controls everything
else in the service.
因此，很多云供应商都不会为您提供主数据库的费用。
So a lot of cloud providers
won't charge you for the master.
我知道 Azure 和 Google Cloud Platform 不会为您负责主数据库。
So I know Azure and Google Cloud Platform
don't charge you for the master.
但亚马逊确实是这样做的。
But Amazon does actually.
所以他们会指控你
So they will actually charge you for
它在库伯内特的内部控制一切
the notes that it's running inside of
Kubernetes to control everything else.
这是 AKS 是 Azure Kubernetes 服务
That's for AKS and
which is Azure Kubernetes Service and
GKE Google的 Kubernetes 引擎，但 Elastic Kubernetes 服务
GKE Google's Kubernetes Engine,
but Elastic Kubernetes Service
就是亚马逊公司负责你的主人
which is the Amazon one does
charge you for the master.
您也可以在不使用诸如 AKS 或 GKE 之类的情况下运行 Kubernetes 。
You can also run Kubernetes without using
like AKS or or GKE or anything like that.
只是在 VM 上自己管理自己的东西，这很困难，对吧 ?
Just on VMs yourself and
run your own stuff, it's just hard, right?
库兹你现在不能只管理各种不同的药
Cuz you have to not now manage not only
all the various different pods and
节点之类的，您还必须管理更多工作的主机。
nodes and things like that, you also have
to manage the hosts which is more work.
那几家公司呢
What about a bunch of companies do it?
好的。
Okay.
这就是大师的东西
So that's what the master is.
就像中央控制飞机就像你告诉库伯奈兹的时候
It's like the central control plane,
like when you tell Kubernetes hey,
把这个扩大到十个节点
scale this up, to ten nodes.
你要和主人谈谈
You're gonna talk to the master and
然后主人会为你做所有的工作
then the master is gonna
do all the work for you.
就像大脑一样
So it's like the brain.
我觉得这是个很好的类比。
I think that's a good analogy.
它是库伯内特群的大脑。
It's the brain of the Kubernetes cluster.
好的，下一个需要知道的是不要混淆的节点
Okay, the next thing that you need to know
about is nodes which is not to be confused
没有 Node.js。
with no Node.js.
这两者之间没有关系
There's no relation between the two.
这些实际上就像工人端点，但是
These are actually like
the worker endpoints, but
那些会真正为你工作的节点
the nodes that are actually
gonna be doing the work for you.
他们是真正与主人交谈过的人
And they're the ones that
actually talked to master.
所以一个节点可以包含多个容器，对吗 ?
So one node can contain
multiple containers, right?
就像 VM 可以有多个容器在其上运行。
Just like a VM can have multiple
containers running on it.
但就像这些类型的端点管理着所有这些
But it's like these kinda endpoints
that are managing all these kind of
工作负载。
workloads for you.
你的一些节点也会是一个容器
Some of your nodes will just
be one container as well and
也可以是正常的
that's also can be normal as well.
特别是如果您有小节点或
Particularly if you have
either small nodes or
你的容器里有很多资源
you have containers that
take a lot of resources.
因此，如果您像我们一样运行 Node.js 服务器，
So, if you're running
a Node.js server like we are,
在一个节点上可能有多个容器。
you'll likely have many
containers on one node.
这种情况经常会发生。
That is kinda frequently what will happen.
所以，从技术上来说，一个节点就像一个部署目标。
So technically a node is
just like a deploy target.
它可以是 VM。
It can be a VM.
它可能是另一个容器
It could be another container.
它可以是一个裸机服务器。
It could be a little bare metal server.
是什么节点就比较不重要了
It's it's relatively unimportant
of what the node is as long as it
除了容器好吗
can except containers, okay?
那么到那时，我们就有了一些叫做 " 药" 的东西。
So at that point then we have
things that are called pods.
它基本上是一个无法分离的单元的部署使用。
And it's basically a deployment use
of the unit that cannot be separated.
所以我想举一个很好的例子。
So I'm trying to think of
a good example of that.
假设你有这个微型服务跟这个微型服务
Let's say you had this micro service
that talk to this micro service under to
紧密联系在一起。
strongly linked together.
也许它就像是用户服务中的密码服务
Maybe it's like a password
service in a user service and
他们就不能分开了
they can't really be separated.
因为他们需要一起部署
Cuz they need to deployed together.
那就被认为是一个吊舱，对。
That would be considered a pod, right.
就像两个或三个容器一样，都是原子的权利。
So be like two or
three containers that are atomic right.
他们不能分开你把它们作为一个吊舱
They can't be split apart so
you deploy them as one pod.
不是一直如此，很多时候你的吊舱都只会是一个容器，
It's not always the case, a lot of times
your pod will only be one container,
就好像它只会是一个你在运作的服务
like it will just be one
service that you're running,
但往往也可以是多方面的。
but frequently it can also
be multiple things together.
然后你就会有这个吊舱
And then you'll have this pod
that talks to this pod and
那些鬼话都说起来就能在
all those pods talking together
will make a service at the end of
你会得到一个人们会说话的用户服务
that you'll have a user service
that people will talk to.
让我们来谈谈服务是什么。
So let's talk about what a service is.
当你有便装当你有这些容器的时候
When you have pods and
when you have these containers,
他们会和对方说话
they will be talking to each other and
这种路由会动态的因为你会在
those kind of routing things will dynamic
because you'll be spinning up pods and
摧毁了便便很可能还能做各种不同的事情
destroying pods and likely to be able to
be doing all sorts of different things.
而且在任何时候你都不知道有多少容器会运行
And at any given time you don't actually
know how many containers will be running
在任何特定时间
at any given time.
所以当服务变得有用时
So that's when services become useful,
因为服务与组成一个服务的一组群相似。
because services are like a group of
pods together that make up one service.
所以你会说，就像结账服务一样。
So you'll have let's say,
like a checkout service.
然后您可以拥有您的购物车服务，与此结帐服务交谈，以及
And then you can have your cart service,
talk to this the checkout service, and
他们在这些 URL上相互交谈
they talk to each other on these one URLs.
尽管这些服务并非完全分开，但它们是一致的
They are consistent despite the fact that
these services don't are totally separate
从彼此之间
from each other.
他们可以以一致的方式相互交流。
They can talk to each
other in a consistent way.
您将这些内容定义为服务。
You define those as a service.
这有点道理吗
That kinda makes sense?
我们要到的地方就有很多东西要从你那里来
We're getting to the point where,
there's just a lot of stuff coming at you.
我想再教你库伯内特
I'm trying to teach you
Kubernetes which again,
就像半个小时就在库伯内特的五天课
there should be like a five day course
just on Kubernetes in like a half hour.
所以这很复杂
So just it is complicated.
如果你觉得很复杂，是因为它很复杂，对吧 ?
If you feel like it is complicated,
it is because it is complicated, right?
所以就知道了
So just be aware of that.
好的，然后你有所谓的 " 部署 " ，那就是
Okay, and then at the end of that you have
what's called a Deployment, which is what
你跟库伯内特说了我想出去的事情
you described to Kubernetes, here's
the things that I would like to go out.
然后你可以有多个不同的部署
And then you can have multiple
different deployments you can have,
您可以回滚部署。
you can roll back deployments.
它就像一个三角洲之间或者类似的变化
It's kind of like a delta between,
or like a change set of,
我有这个现在我想去了对吧
I had this and now I wanna go here, right?
所以你的定义是不一样的
So you're defining like
something that's different and
如果 " 部署 " 出错并且您说 " 嘿" ，那么将该链回滚到它的位置
if that Deployment goes wrong and you say
hey, roll that chain set back to where it
在中断之前，对，然后您也可以部署更多的部署。
was before the broke, right and then you
can deploy more deployments as well.
所以你可以在你的集群中定义不同时间的差异。
So you're kind of defining differences
over time in your cluster.